# **Daniel Niknam**



linkedin.com/in/mhmdniknam



https://niknam.org



mhmd.niknam@gmail.com

## **Summary**

A skilled and self-educated developer with more than ten years of experience in web development, building a range of advanced applications using Ruby and PHP. An experienced technical leader with excellent communication skills and enthusiasm for learning. The fine knowledge of project lifecycle makes me a good candidate for implementing applications from design to deploy.

## Experience



#### Software Developer

**Envato** 

Jan 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

# Senior Backend Developer

**Bugloos** 

Sep 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Senior Backend Developer

Bugloos is a project based that provides consultancy and web development. My responsibility as a senior developer was developing the best possible solution for customers and as a team leader I was responsible for review, test and translate customer needs to use-cases.

PHP, NodeJS, Angular, Symfony, RESTful, RabbitMQ, MySQL, ElasticSearch, CircleIO, Teamleader, Pivotal Tracker

Challenges:

- \* Develop a complex booking software
- \* Develop a complicated workflow
- \* Design and implement complete chat system using WebRTC and WebSocket
- \* Migrate from traditional application development to modular development
- \* Manage a group of developers
- \* Project management and code review
- \* Mentoring and pair programming



### **Senior Backend Developer**

#### **Round Table Apps**

Jul 2016 - Sep 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Ruby on Rails was our first choice for backend and react for the frontend. We implemented many e-commerce projects, ranged from simple shopping website to enterprise B2B which would connect wholesalers to retailers using a dynamic and innovative workflow. Because of the clean and well-tested code base (around 80% test coverage), we never faced a critical bug or issue in production.

Ruby, NodeJS, Ruby on Rails, SQS, EC2, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Jenkins, Jira, Confluence, Selenium, Sidekiq Challenges:

- \* Develop smart/async crawling application
- \* Develop various e-commerce projects
- \* Standardize RESTful API in all project
- \* Optimize and review team member works

### **Web Developer**

**VADA House of Mobile** 

Aug 2013 - Jul 2016 (3 years)

My career in VADA started with maintaining and developing a 10K line vanilla PHP script (in only five files) and continued with converting it to a micro-service based Golang application which had almost more than ten times better performance and speed. My implementation of an SMS gateway system using the adapter design pattern with Symfony components was the company's starting point into the micro-services world. We used RabbitMQ as the message broker to connect our event-driven services to each other, helping our dream to come true.

PHP, Gearman, Symfony Components, RabbitMQ, PostgreSQL, Laravel, Lumen, MicroService, EventDriven, Golang

Challenges:

- \* Develop text games using Symfony components
- \* Develop flexible and easy to extend SMS gateway
- \* Translate business goals, feature concepts, and customer needs into prioritized product requirements and use-cases.
- \* Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products

## PHP Developer

Aftab Group

Jun 2012 - Apr 2013 (11 months)

- \* Wrote CMS applications in MVC architecture using PHP
- \* Designed MVC application components

#### Education

# 📕 institution of higher education ooj

Associate's degree, Computer Engineering 2016 - 2020

#### **Skills**

PHP • MySQL • JavaScript • Python • Web Development • Ruby • Django • PostgreSQL • Ruby on Rails • OOP